Tom Gehrels Papers, 1894-2011 (bulk 1961-2000)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series IV: Research Files, 1920-2006.
  - Subseries 11: Science Notes: chronologically arranged, 1951-1990
    - : Polarized emissions, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - : Techniques, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Series V: Travel files, 1973-2012
  This series is arranged chronologically. The bulk of the trips are for professional reasons. There are many trips to India from 1975 through 1998.
  - Trip around the world, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Lecture tour through Europe, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - India trip, 1975-1979 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Trip to Venezuela, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Japan, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Trip to Sri Lanka and India, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Travel to China, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Dubrovnik, Yugoslavia – IAU Sixth Regional Astronomy meeting, October 19-22, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - India and Baltimore, Maryland, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - India and Japan, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Russia and India, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - India, 1992-1994 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Chelyabinsk-70, Russia, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Steinem, India, and Sri Lanka, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Japan and India, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Taiwan and India, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Galapagos, June 21-July 3, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Russia and Atmospheric Science course, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Political Forum, the Historical Society, Boston, MA, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous trip files from 2007-2008 and 2010-2012 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Series VI Instructional/teaching files/courses and class notes, 1969-2001
  - Astronomy 213: Polarimetry of stars and planets, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - The Universe and humanity origin and destiny, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - The Universe and humanity origin and destiny, spring 1990 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - The Universe and humanity origin and destiny, spring 1992 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - The Universe and humanity: Origin and destiny- instructor’s copy, Spring, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - PTYS 105: The Universe and humanity: Origin and future, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - NATS 102: The Universe and humanity: A Worldview of the 21st century, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - NATS 102: The atoms within us a worldwide view, December, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - NATS 102: Universe and humanity, ethics and action, - instructor’s copy, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Evaluations for NATS 102 and Planetary Science 105, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Evaluations for NATS 102 and Planetary Science 105, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
- Series VII: Photographs by subject, circa 1963-2000
  - Observatories, Instruments, equipment, circa 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - People, circa 1978-2000 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Planets, stars, moon, etc., circa 1968-1986 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Gordon Conference, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Series VIII: Newspaper Clippings pertaining to Dr. Tom Gehrels, circa 1973-1999
  - Clippings (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Slides
  - Subseries 1: These slides are arranged into slide sheets and then into folders by subject. The majority of slides are not dated.
    - Biomedical Communications University of Arizona, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Observatories, telescopes and other instrutments, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Planets, moons, satellites, asteroids, stars, comets (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Spacewatch, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Ballooning PN, undated (Box 21, Container 1)
    - Brussels lectures, 1945 (Box 21, Container 2)
    - Spacewatch, March 1979 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Class NATS 102, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - The Planets, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Ballooning, 1804-1974 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - People and labeled slides, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Figures and negatives for unknown papers, talks and books, undated (Box 21A)
- Audio Visual materials, 1960-1993
  - Subseries 1: 8 mm films
    - Balloon footage, Otto Winzen, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Launching balloon, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2: 16 mm film, circa 1962-1993
    - Balloon footage, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Jupiter approach, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - JVAHV Satellite?, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, August 1972 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Saturn simulation, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Saturn, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Very good launch toward moon-good color launch 7268, original, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Men working at unidentified observatory, University of Arizona, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - The Voyagers NASA TV News, February 1979 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Voyager II encounter, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Operation polariscope roll number 15, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Operation polariscope roll number 16, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Polariscope-1, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Polariscope-2, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Polariscope-3, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Polariscope-4, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Original balloon launch Glen Canyon Dam, December 1962 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Explorations of the planets, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Operation polariscope–Page launch #1411 (color original), undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Operation polariscope #2246 (color original), undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Operation polariscope, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Balloon footage, Calvin De Fraves?, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Mariner/Jupiter/Saturn, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - P10 – LAB copy, August 1972 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Unknown title, unknown date (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Audiotape - trip to Venezuela, 1977-1979 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Audiotape – Tom Gerhels lecture-IUCAA, August 17, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - VHS Tape – Spacewatch for DPS meeting, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Series XI: 3.5 Disks:
  Boxes 25 and 26; contain 86 disks, very few of the disks are dated, there are numerous subjects such as; grant files, proposals, donations, reports, Spacewatch publications, Gehrels publications, Space Science Series files, and the book “Origin”, etc.
- Series XII: CD's
  - Final for talks of, February 2010 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Prof. Tom Gehrels talk (PRL), October 10, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - 2. Prof. Tom Gehrels talk (PRL), October 10, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Final figures – Sanya for Gehrels, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Prakash/Gehrels, March 11, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - India Pictures, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Images selected by Prakash, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Power point, January 28, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Photographs - Jones Photos, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Gehrels FOS2.doc, October 27, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Gehrels FOS2.doc, October 27 and 28, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Add to Sanya’s figures, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Cover page (tiff format), undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Sanya 2, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Planetary Images, undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Paragevechtsgroep (paratroopers) van de KNIL, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Gehrels Book – color, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - NASA awards to Thomas Gehrels the NASA Medal for Exceptional Scientific Achievement, August 19, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Polariscope flight, February 9, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 2)